NullInjectorError: No provider\h for the injectable class.\h
NullInjectorError: No provider\h for the injectable class.\h
You'll encounter this error when\h you attempt to inject a service,\h\h
当你尝试注入一个服务，却没有声明对应的提供者时 就会遇到本错误。
without declaring the corresponding provider. In other words, your code is attempting to use\h\h
换句话说，你的代码尝试使用某个依赖
a dependency, but Angular has no way to find\h or inject that dependency, because there is\h\h
但是 Angular 却无法找到或注入那个依赖
currently no provider pointing to it. But what is a provider exactly?\h\h
因为目前没有任何提供者指向它 但所谓的“提供者”到底是什么呢？
Think of it like a prescription for a medication,\h where the prescription is a provider and the\h\h
你可以把它看一个药物的处方，这个“处方”就是提供者
medication is an injectable service. What the\h error is telling us is that we're trying to\h\h
而这个药物就是用于注入的服务。本错误告诉我们的是
use a medication that has not been prescribed.\h There are two places we can address the issue:\h\h
我们正试图使用一种没有处方的药物。 可以用两种方式解决此问题：
the injectable decorator or the provider's array\h in an ngModule. In either case, a provider is\h\h
@Injectable 装饰器，或者在 ngModule 的 providers 数组中 无论哪种方式，提供者都由三部分主要信息构成
composed of three main pieces of information. First, it needs to know where to make the\h\h
首先，它需要知道在哪里让这个类可用
class available, like the root of\h the application or a feature module.\h\h
比如应用的根模块或特性模块。
And second, it needs a token for locating that\h class within the dependency injection system. The\h\h
其次，它需要一个令牌（Token），以便在依赖注入体系中定位那个类
token is the class type that has been decorated.\h In most cases the token will be the same as the\h\h
这里的令牌是一个带有装饰器的类的类型 在多数情况下，此令牌和你要提供的类是同一个
class that you want to provide, however, it's\h possible to provide a third piece of information\h\h
不过，你还可以提供第三部分信息，比如
like useClass to provide an entirely different\h class or useValue to provide a raw value.\h
用 useClass 来提供完全不同的一个类，或者用 useValue 来提供一个原始值
Let's start by taking a look at a couple\h of common examples and quick fixes,\h\h
让我们看一组常见的范例及其快速修复方式
then we'll take a more detailed look at\h injectors and providers to understand why\h\h
然后我们会深入看一下注入器和提供者，以便在更基础的层面上
this error happens at a more fundamental level. In our code base we have a service decorated\h\h
理解为什么会发生此错误 在我们的代码中，有一个带有 @Injectable 装饰器的服务
with @Injectable, but currently the service\h has not been provided to any ngModule within\h\h
但目前，该服务还没有在应用内的任何 ngModule 中提供
the application. When we attempt to inject\h it in the constructor of the AppComponent,\h\h
当我们试图在 AppComponent 的构造函数中中注入它时
the result is the NullInjectorError. The error\h message itself points to the offending class.\h\h
就会导致 NullInjectorError。此错误信息指出了出错的类
Now there are two main ways we might address the\h issue. If we want to provide the class throughout\h\h
现在，我们有两种主要的方式解决此问题 如果我们要在整个应用范围内提供这个类
the entire application we can use the providedIn:\h 'root' option. That'll provide a global singleton\h\h
可以使用 providedIn: 'root' 选项。它会提供一个全局单例
that can be used anywhere in the application\h and clears the error. However, that may not\h\h
此单例可以用于应用中的任何地方，并消除本错误
always be the optimal solution. In some cases,\h it may be more efficient to scope a service to\h\h
不过，这可能并不总是最合适的解决方案 某些情况下，更有效的方式是把某个服务局限在某个特性模块内部。
a feature module. And that can be achieved by\h providing an ngModule class as the providedIn\h\h
这可以通过把某个 ngModule 类作为 providedIn 选项的值来实现
option. That makes it possible to exclude this\h code from the app's main JavaScript bundle\h\h
这样就让我们可以从应用的主 JS 包中排除这部分代码，按需惰性加载
and lazy load it when it becomes needed to improve\h load time performance. That's ideal when you have\h\h
这可以提升加载性能。当你有一个要在独立模块中书踹死的服务时，这很好
a service that's used by an individual module,\h but what if a service is required by multiple lazy\h\h
但是如果该服务被多个惰性加载模块使用时怎么办呢？
loaded modules? In that case you may want each\h module to create its own instance of the service.\h\h
这种情况下，你可能希望每个模块都为本服务创建它自己的实例。
That can be achieved with the providedIn:\h 'any' option. Instead of a singleton,\h\h
这可以通过 providedIn: 'any' 选项来实现
this option will instantiate a new service for\h each module that injects it. And one other option\h\h
这种方式下，服务不是单例的，而是为每个模块创建一个实例
to also be aware of is providedIn: 'platform',\h which is relevant to projects that use multiple\h\h
还有一个选项是 providedIn: 'platform'
Angular applications on a single page, such as\h web components with Angular elements for example.\h\h
它适用于那些要在同一个页面中使用多个 Angular 应用的项目 比如通过 Angular Elements 实现的 Web Components
providedIn: 'platform' will make the service\h available to all applications on that page.\h
在同一个页面中的所有 Angular 应用中可用
In total that's four different\h ways to provide a service.\h
总之，一共有四种不同的方式来提供某个服务。
'root' instantiates a singleton\h for an entire Angular app,\h
'root' 会为整个 Angular 应用实例化一个单例
a module class provides a\h singleton for just that module,\h
“模块类”会单独为那个模块提供一个单例
'any' provides an instance for\h each module that injects it,\h
'any' 会为每个注入它的模块提供一个实例
and 'platform' provides a singleton\h for multiple Angular applications.\h
而 'platform' 会为多个 Angular 应用提供一个单例
Now it's also worth noting that you can provide\h a service directly in the ngModule decorator.\h\h
另外，你还可以在 ngModule 装饰器中直接提供某个服务
Import the service you want to provide then\h add it to the provider's array within the\h\h
只要导入你要提供的服务 然后把它加到 ngModule 装饰器的 providers 数组中就可以了
ngModule decorator. This pattern also creates a\h provider, however it's generally not the preferred\h\h
这种模式也会创建一个提供者，不过通常不建议使用这种方式
approach because it makes the code more difficult\h to tree shake when a service has not been injected\h\h
因为它会让这些代码在没有任何地方注入它的时候，难以摇树优化掉
anywhere. Now in many cases you may encounter the\h NullInjectorError from a third-party dependency\h\h
很多情况下，你可能遇到来自第三方依赖或
or one of Angular's built-in modules. For\h example, imagine we import the HTTP client into\h\h
比如，如果在 AppComponent 中导入 HTTP Client，然后
our AppComponent, then inject it as a dependency\h in the constructor. That also throws an error,\h\h
把它注入为构造函数中的一个依赖项，同样会抛出一个错误
but you might be wondering why something built\h into Angular would not have a provider. There\h\h
但是你可能想不通为什么 Angular 内置的东西还会没有提供者
are only a handful of minimal services built into\h Angular core. Almost everything else is isolated\h\h
这是因为只有极少数服务才内置到了 Angular 内核中 其它的一切几乎都拆到了自己的模块中
in its own module. What that means is that in\h order to use the HTTP client, we need to import\h\h
这意味着要使用 HTTP Client，我们就要
its corresponding ngModule in the module that\h depends on it, which in our case is the AppModule,\h\h
在依赖它的模块（AppModule ）中导入其对应的 ngModule
and we do that by adding it to its imports array.\h Now that we know how to fix the issue, let's talk\h\h
我们可以通过把它加入到 AppModule 的 imports 数组中来实现 现在，我们知道了如何修复此错误，接下来我们谈谈注入器
about injectors. When Angular is bootstrapped, it\h creates an application-wide injector. Its job is\h\h
当 Angular 启动时，它会创建一个全应用级注入器
to create and manage dependencies, and it does\h that by maintaining a collection of providers.\h\h
它的职责是创建和管理依赖，它会维护一个提供者的集合
Each provider contains a token or class type that\h tells Angular where to find the injectable value.\h\h
每个提供者具有一个令牌或类的类型 它会告诉 Angular 去哪里寻找要注入的值
In most cases a provider is created with\h the @Injectable decorator. When that class\h\h
大多数情况下，提供者是通过 @Injectable 装饰器来创建的
is then referenced in the constructor of a\h component for example, the injector will use\h\h
比如当某个组件的构造函数中引用了这个类的时候，
the provider to find the existing instance of\h that class or instantiate a new one if required.\h\h
注入器就会使用此提供者来寻找该类的现有实例，或者按需实例化一个新的
Every dependency needs to have at least one\h provider, and that brings us to the root of\h\h
每个依赖项都需要至少一个提供者，否则就会抛出 NullInjectorError
the NullInjectorError. If there's no provider,\h it just doesn't work. Let's go ahead and recap.\h\h
如果没有提供者，它就不能正常工作。我们来回顾一下
When you encounter the NullInjectorError, it\h means a service was injected without the necessary\h\h
当你遇到 NullInjectorError 时 它表示某个要注入的服务没有必要的提供者
provider. The first step is to find the offending\h class. If it's one of your own injectable classes,\h\h
第一步是找到那个导致错误的类。如果它是你自己的 @Injectable 类之一
you can provide it in the root of the application\h or provide it in an ngModule. If it's related to\h\h
你可以在应用的根或者某个 ngModule 中提供它。
a third party dependency, you're likely\h missing an ngModule import. Determine\h\h
如果它和某个第三方依赖有关，可能是你忘了导入某个 ngModule
where that service is provided, then import the\h corresponding ngModule. For additional details\h\h
你要找出那个服务是在哪里提供的，然后导入对应的 ngModule
and examples check out the dependency injection\h guide in the official Angular documentation
欲知详情和范例，请阅读Angular官方文档的“依赖注入”指南